[
    {
        "front": "のります ❘\n「でんしゃに～」",
        "back": "ride, get on [a train]",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "おります ❘❘",
        "back": "get off",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "のりかえます ❘❘",
        "back": "change (trains, etc.)",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "あびます ❘❘ \n「シャワーを～」",
        "back": "take [a shower]",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "いれます ❘❘",
        "back": "put in, insert",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "だします ❘",
        "back": "take out, withdraw",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "はいります ❘\n「だいがくに～」",
        "back": "enter [university]",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "でます ❘❘\n「だいがくに～」",
        "back": "graduate from [university]",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "やめます ❘❘\n「かいしゃを～」",
        "back": "quit or retire from [a company]",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "おします ❘",
        "back": "push, press",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "わかい",
        "back": "young",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "ながい",
        "back": "long",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "みじかい",
        "back": "short",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "あかるい",
        "back": "bright, light",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "くらい",
        "back": "dark",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "せが たかい",
        "back": "tall (referring to person)",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "あたま が いい",
        "back": "intelligent, smart",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "からだ",
        "back": "body",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "あたま",
        "back": "head",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "かみ",
        "back": "hair",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "かお",
        "back": "face",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "め",
        "back": "eye",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "みみ",
        "back": "ear",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "くち",
        "back": "mouth",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "は",
        "back": "tooth",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "おなか",
        "back": "stomach",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "あし",
        "back": "leg, foot",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "サービス",
        "back": "service",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジョギング",
        "back": "jogging (～をします jog)",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "シャワー",
        "back": "shower",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "みどり",
        "back": "green, greenery",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "「お」てら",
        "back": "Buddhist temple",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "じんじゃ",
        "back": "Shinto shrine",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "りゅがくせい",
        "back": "foreign student",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "―ばん",
        "back": "number-",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうやって",
        "back": "in what way, how",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "どの～",
        "back": "which～(used for three or more)",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "いいえ、まだまだです",
        "back": "[No,] I still have a long way to go",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "おひきだしですか",
        "back": "Do you want to withdraw cash?",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "まず",
        "back": "first of all",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "キャッシュカード",
        "back": "password, PIN number",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "あんしょばんご",
        "back": "next, as a next step",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "きんがく",
        "back": "amount of money",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "かくにん",
        "back": "confirmation (～します :confirm)",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボタン",
        "back": "button",
        "chapter": "N5 C16"
    }
]